ALISTAIR EVERETT

Stallovegen 14, 9016 Tromsø, Norway GITHUB: https://github.com/alistaireverett EMAIL: alistair.everett@gmail.com PHONE: +47 939 68 985

Interdisciplinary Research Scientist with experience in high resolution fluid dynamics modelling and a background in engineering. Skills in scientific programming, primarily with Python, and experience compiling and running codes in a linux environment and on high performance computing clusters. Interests and developing skills in data science and machine learning.

PRESENT

Present – 2016-09

Research Scientist - Norwegian Polar Institute, Norway

- Finite element fluid dynamics modelling of meltwater plumes at Kronebreen, Svalbard.
- Applying model to real terminus geometries from sideways sonar scans of an ice front.
- Developing simplified plume parameterisations for large-scale ocean models.
- Analysis of seal-collected oceanographic data and dive locations around plumes.

EXPERIENCE

2016-08 – 2013-01

PhD - Swansea University Glaciology Group, UK

- THESIS TITLE: Observing and Modelling Meltwater at the Termini of Tidewater Glaciers
- Developed existing fluid dynamics code (F90) to model plumes at tidewater glaciers.
- Compiled and ran model on local and national HPC clusters.
- Developed Python code to model water-driven fracture on glaciers.
- Automatic classification of surface meltwater using MODIS and Landsat imagery.
- Analysis of observational plume data including LiDAR and timelapse imagery.
- Taught on modules including Geographic Information Systems and Research Methods.

2012-12 –

Graduate Bridges and Design Engineer - North Yorkshire County Council, UK

2011-10

- · Positions in Highways Operations and Bridges and Design Services.
- Project managed four projects with budgets up to £160,000 each.

2011-09 -

Research Assistant - UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK

2011-07

- Development of a rotating three-dimensional fluid dynamics simulation of a turbine.
- Used C++ and Matlab to automatically generate geometries and optimise power output.

EDUCATION

2011-07 -	WEng (Hons)	Civil Engineering -	UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK
-----------	-------------	---------------------	------------------------

2007-09 DISSERTATION: Experimental Investigations on Thermohaline Circulation

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Software/Environments Experienced (> 2 years) Linux, Windows, Quantum GIS, MTEX, Git, High Performance Computing Familiar (< 2 years) ArcMap, node.js, Tensorflow, Keras, (< 2 years) Aws, Heroku, Spark Languages Python (numpy, scipy, pandas, scikit-learn), Fortran, MATLAB C++, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bash

Courses

2017-10	Norskkurs (A2) - Folkeuniversitetet, Tromsø
2018-10	Machine Learning A-Z: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science - UDEMY [ONLINE]
2018-04	Python for Data Science and Machine Learning - UDEMY [ONLINE]
2017-10	Norskkurs (A1) - Multilingo, Tromsø
2014-09	Fluid Dynamics Summer School (FDSE) - UNIVERSITY OF CAMBRIDGE, UK
2014-08	International Summer School in Glaciology - McCarthy, Alaska, USA
2014-02	AG-825 Glaciology Course - University Centre in Svalbard, Norway
2014-01	Communicating Science - SCIENCE MUSEUM LONDON, UK

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2018-04	Austfonna Glacial Mass Balance Field Program - Nordaustlandet, Svalbard
2017-04	British Stauning Alps Expedition 2017 - EAST GREENLAND
2013-06 – 2013-09	Field Assistant - SERMILIK FJORD, SOUTH EAST GREENLAND
2009–2011	Club President - Bath University Mountaineering Club

GRANTS AND AWARDS

2017-11	Svalbard Science Conference - Best Early Career Researcher Poster
2017-04	Stauning Alps Expedition (Various grants totalling: £22383)
2015-12	Swansea University Team Maker Competition 2015 (First Prize)
2015-10	NERC High Performance Computing Grant (£ 5 600)
2015–2013	7 travel and development bursaries (Various grants totalling £ 3 500)

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

Lead: Everett, A. et al. (2018) Subglacial discharge plume behaviour revealed by

CTD-instrumented ringed seals, Nature: Scientific Reports.

Everett, A. *et al.* (2016) Water Levels in Crevasses Controlled by Basal Water Pressures at Helheim Glacier, South East Greenland, *Journal of Geophysical Research: Earth Surface*.

Co-author: Vallot, D. et al. (2018) Effects of undercutting and sliding on calving: a coupled approach

applied to Kronebreen, Svalbard, *The Cryosphere*.

Moloney, V. *et al.* (2016) Investigation of wind and tidal forcing on stratified flows in Greenland fjords with TELEMAC-3D, *European Journal of Computational Mechanics*.

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Mountain First Aid, Crevasse Rescue, PADI Open Water Diver Certification, Full Clean UK Driving License, intermediate Norwegian, basic German and French.